♪♪
Quiet, Mr. Matlock,
or I'll hold you in contempt.
No, that's not all.
Where were you...
Objection, Your Honor.
Mr. Matlock is engaging
in absurd speculation,
and then using that speculation to
support his unfounded accusation.
If client is guilty...
We're talking about murder...
- No!
- Overruled.
Order! Mr. Matlock, you
must restrain yourself.
- We, the jury, find the defendant guilty.
- This is all speculation, Your Honor!
- We find the defendant not guilty.
- I object. The witness is not on trial.
Mr. Matlock, you
are in contempt.
- Your Honor, I object.
- Bailiff, you are hereby instructed...
to remove Mr. Matlock from
this courtroom immediately.
The witness is
fabricating the entire...
Mr. Matlock, you are
incapable of sticking to the facts
and refraining from
these courtroom theatrics!
Quiet! I'll hold
you in contempt!
- That's enough!
- Do you understand?
That's enough, Mr. Matlock.
I told the Burkes you had
that appointment at 5:00,
so they're just going to meet us
at the restaurant, if that's okay?
Fine, fine.
I have an appointment
at 5:00 tonight?
- Friday night.
- Oh.
I've got a new client.
I promised I'd meet him at
Stumpy Point after we adjourn here.
You're not going to drive all the
way to Stumpy Point this afternoon?
It's just Stumpy Point.
It's only 9:00 in the morning,
and you can't even open
your mouth without yawning.
Mmm.
Has it occurred to
you that you might be
spreading yourself a
little thin these days?
Oh, it's just against my nature
to turn down work, you know?
Mmm.
You're cutting it a little
close, aren't you, Ben?
Huh?
This isn't a business
deal that can go sour, Ben.
I can't afford to lose here.
Oh, Frank,
I've been doing this so long
I've got it down to a science.
It takes me exactly 20 minutes to
drive from my house to the parking lot,
two minutes to walk from the
parking lot to the courtroom,
nine seconds to
organize my papers.
All rise.
And about two seconds longer
to get to my feet than it used to.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
No more questions.
Mr. Matlock?
Thank you, Your Honor.
Uh, Lieutenant, were
you able to find anybody
who saw Mr. Englewood
leave the bakery that day?
Who?
My client, Mr. Englewood.
You mean Mr. Mitchell.
Uh...
Yeah. Yeah, Mr. Mitchell.
What did I say?
Englewood.
Nah, I... I meant Mr. Mitchell.
In answer to your question, no.
We didn't find anyone who
saw him leave the bakery.
Thank you, Lieutenant.
Remember me?
Frank Mitchell?
Yeah.
I opened my mouth to say your name,
and another client's name popped out.
Try not to lose interest
in my case, will you?
Officer Taggerman, will
you please tell the court
what you found when you
searched the defendant's garage?
Objection.
The warrant Officer
Taggerman had
when he searched my
client's garage was invalid.
It was issued without
probable cause.
Anything seized in that
search is therefore inadmissible.
But Officer Taggerman
didn't know that.
He believed the
warrant was valid.
The warrant was invalid.
Who cares what Officer
Taggerman believed?
Well, the United States
Supreme Court does.
According to United
States vs. Leon,
good faith belief
justifies a search
whether the warrant
is valid or not.
The United States vs. who?
Leon.
When did this happen?
Late last year.
Objection overruled.
The gun seized by
Officer Taggerman
will be admitted into evidence.
What is going on, Ben?
Oh, I... I got overruled.
It's not the end of the world.
We've got to talk.
Things will look better once we start
presenting our case, I guarantee it.
You just have to hang on.
Ben...
This isn't working, Ben.
Frank... Frank, now,
you're overreacting.
Just... I'm replacing you, Ben.
I'm sorry, but I need an attorney
I have more confidence in.
I'm hiring Edwin McClure.
Edwin McClure?
The man wins one little
case and writes a book.
You can't be serious.
I like his approach,
and I like him.
I feel like I can relate to
him better than I can to you.
Relate?
McClure and I are the same
generation. We think alike.
Edwin McClure is
dynamic and on top of it,
and I want him
representing my case.
Well,
it's your choice.
I'll ask for a recess and
speak to Mr. McClure.
Thanks, Ben.
And, again, I'm sorry.
You're withdrawing
from the case?
Uh, that's right, Your Honor.
I'm turning it over
to Mr. McClure here.
But why?
Oh, well, uh, personal reasons.
Uh, I've... I've decided to
retire from the practice of law.
- What?
- You have?
Well, it, uh... It-it had
to come sometime,
and, uh... and it just turned
out that this is a good time.
Well, this comes
as quite a shock.
I guess if anybody
deserves a rest, you do.
Good luck, Ben.
You'll be missed.
Uh, defense's motion is granted.
♪ Softly and tenderly ♪
♪ Jesus is calling ♪
♪ Calling for you ♪
♪ And for me ♪
♪ See by the portholes ♪
♪ He's watching and waiting ♪
♪ Waiting for you ♪
♪ And for me ♪
♪ Come home ♪
♪♪
♪ Ye who are weary ♪
- ♪ Come home ♪
- Ben?
- Huh? In here.
Oh, hi. Hi. What's up?
I see you're shining
your shoes there.
Oh, yeah.
A man can't take too
much pride in his feet.
What's up with you?
- What's up with us?
- Yeah.
Well, Julie just called
and said you'd retired.
Oh, oh, oh, oh.
Well, yeah.
Just like that?
Without any
warning, you retired?
That's right.
Because Frank Mitchell
fired you, you retired?
Oh, no, no, no, no.
I just figured it was time.
- Ben?
- Uh-huh?
Is there something
you haven't told us?
- Like what?
- Like, are you sick?
No. No, no, no.
I just figured it was time.
And I'm leaving the office
and the practice to you.
There'll be, uh, more
than enough work
for both of you for a long time.
I'm going down
tonight and get my stuff.
- Tonight?
- Yeah.
There's files and stuff.
Look at that boot. Huh?
Mmm.
♪♪
Oh, hi.
I was waiting for
you at your house.
I was starting to get worried.
Well, I'm sorry.
I just thought I'd come over here
tonight and pack up some of this stuff.
Oh, leave it here.
I'm sure Conrad and
Michelle won't mind.
Oh, no. They can...
They can use the space.
See?
♪♪
I couldn't remember
my client's name.
Oh, that was just
a slip of the tongue.
It happens to everybody.
Yeah, I guess. Yeah. Yeah.
I didn't know about that
Supreme Court ruling.
Well, sometimes I don't know.
Those rulings come down so fast.
Yeah, I guess. Yeah.
You've just been
working too hard, that's all.
You've got too many
cases. You're tired.
Yeah. Yeah. Maybe.
Or...
Are you going to say,
"I'm not tired, I'm old"?
No, I wasn't going to say that.
Of course, I am.
I mean... I mean,
not much but some.
Hey, are we still on for Friday?
Or are you too ancient
to take a lady to dinner?
Oh, I'll pick you up at 6:00.
You'll... You'll recognize
me. I'll be wearing a gray suit.
Good morning, Miss McArdle.
Oh, top of the morning
to you, Mr. Matlock.
Or bottom, now that
I look at my watch.
Well, will you be having
breakfast or lunch?
Surprise me.
Is this what you're
going to be doing now,
spending half the day in bed?
Maybe.
Well, that's what my
Grandpa Aloysius did
when he retired.
He'd go to bed at
midnight, wake up at noon.
Day in, day out.
Sounds like the life.
Well, he was dead in
two years, of course.
I mean, the body can only
stand so much inactivity.
And then there was
my second cousin Paul,
the retired policeman.
He shot his wife and the
family dog in a fit of rage
and then turned
the gun on himself.
Everyone survived.
He was a terrible shot.
It sounds like
retirement in your family
is a pretty dangerous thing.
I won't even begin to tell you
what Uncle Bernard
did when he retired.
I don't think I've ever heard
you speak of an Uncle Bernard.
That's because now we
have to call him Aunt Bernice.
Oh.
- I still can't believe it.
- Me either.
I guess we'll have to.
It's not like he doesn't
deserve to retire.
Yeah.
I never thought about it, but I
guess we all have to retire someday.
- I'm going to miss him.
- Well, I'm gonna see him.
- Oh, we're all going to see him.
- We're all gonna see him, yeah.
It just won't be the same.
You know what?
Let's give him a
retirement party.
A surprise retirement party.
- Yeah.
- What about Friday?
- That's perfect.
He's taking me to
Lavelle's at 6:00.
This is great. You know what?
This is going to knock his head off.
- It'll be fun.
- We gotta get lots of people.
And let's have something
to eat besides hot dogs.
Anything but hot dogs.
I've never known
what Ben sees in them.
Oh.
Ow!
That's right. 6:00 at Lavelle's.
Okay. I'll see you then.
- Sorry I'm late.
- Hey, Julie.
Look at all the decorations.
We kind of got carried away.
In fact, it might be a good idea if
you and Ben didn't show up till 6:30.
- Give us a chance to set everything up.
- I'll give him a call.
- How many people have you told?
- 50, and almost all of them are coming.
He's not home.
I sure hope he's not
on his way over here.
Me, too.
Want to do the dots?
Yes.
I'm calling my house.
Maybe he left me a message.
You guys, that's beautiful.
Uh, Julie, it's, uh... It's Ben.
Listen, I'm not going to be
able to make dinner tonight.
My neighbor is mad at me,
and I kind of need
some time to myself,
so I'm just going to leave town
and do a little fishing, okay?
I'll... I'll call you
when I get back.
And I'll take you to whatever
restaurant you want to go to then.
Uh-oh.
♪♪
Hello. Car trouble.
Sí. Blown head gasket.
Oh. Where are you headed?
Oak Creek. It's
just up the road.
I have a map. See?
Oh. Where did you get this?
Mr. Jones send it to me.
He's my new boss.
Owns a big farm by Oak Creek.
Oh, you've got a new job.
I have a job in Ford in Mobile.
This one is better. More dinero.
Oh. What do you do?
Mechanic.
I fix farm machines...
Tractors, combines, harrowbeds.
I meet Mr. Jones at a
tractor shop in Mobile.
He see I do good work,
promised to pay me double.
- Oh.
- But this is big problem.
Yeah.
Well, I tell you what, get
your stuff and I'll give you a lift.
You're a very nice man.
Oak Creek. Yeah.
Yeah. Okay. Here.
Here. I'll help you get this...
- You live in Oak Creek?
- Oh, no. Atlanta.
They have farms there?
Well, no... no,
not right in town.
I'll tell you what they do
have, though... lawyers.
That's what I was... a lawyer.
Retired.
Now you fish.
Yeah. Ben Matlock.
I'm Roman Elonzo
Comaneros Lomas.
- Ramon.
You like to fish?
I'm going to learn to like it.
You have time to do now what you
want to do, not what you have to do.
You are a lucky man.
Well, you're young,
got your life ahead of
you, got a brand-new job.
You're the lucky one, Ramon.
Where did you learn about
all this farm equipment?
- Back home in El Salvador.
- Uh-huh.
My family is still there.
Here is my mother, my
two sisters and my brothers.
- You're the oldest?
- Sí.
I send all my money to them.
- Someday they live here, too.
- Ah.
Fasten your seatbelt.
- Fill her up?
- Yeah.
- I come back for my things.
- Okay.
Nice day.
Elbow aches. Gonna rain.
Mmm.
Oh. Whereabouts
is the, uh, uh...
- Right there.
- Okay, thanks.
Hi. My truck broke
down on the road.
I need for someone
to bring it here.
- So you need a tow?
- Sí.
Name?
Ramon Comaneros.
Spell it, slowly.
C-O...
What you got on that rag?
- Ammonia on it.
- It smells awful.
Don't streak, don't run,
cheaper than dirt and
cleans my fingernails.
14.55.
Okay.
Everything is taken care of.
You don't want me to
drive you to the farm?
I called Mr. Jones.
He says go to his office above the
hardware store, and he'll drive me.
Adios and gracias,
Señor Matlock.
- You are a kind man.
- It was a pleasure, Ramon.
Gracias.
- Good luck to you. Bye.
- Bye-bye.
Oh, thanks.
Did you check my oil?
You didn't ask me to.
No, I guess I didn't.
♪♪
Yes?
Uh, Mr. Jones?
- Yes.
- Uh...
My name is Ben Matlock.
I just gave a young man,
Ramon Comaneros,
a ride into town.
Oh, yeah. He told me about you.
- Sit down.
- Oh, thank you. Thank you.
Is he still here?
No. My foreman just
drove him out to the farm.
Oh, dag-gone.
Is something wrong?
Well, he left these pictures
of his family in El
Salvador in my car,
and they mean a lot to him,
and I'm sure he'd want
them back right away.
Well, I'll be driving out
there in about an hour.
I'll see that he gets them.
What kind... What
kind of farm you got?
Well, I got about,
uh, 600 acres in
Timothy right now...
About, uh, 500 in wheat,
uh, 200 in field corn,
and I'm running cattle
on about 70 acres.
Oh, that sounds good. Yeah.
I just retired, and I'm
trying to kind of figure out
what to do with myself
for the next 20 years.
Well, unless you enjoy
being on the brink of
bankruptcy 90 percent of the time,
I'd stay away from farming.
Uh, give me the pictures.
I'll make sure he gets them.
Uh, that's okay. I'll...
I'll take them to him.
I... I got nothing
else to do today.
It's a big farm, Mr. Matlock.
- You'll never be able to find him.
- I'll just keep looking till I do.
I got nothing else
on my calendar.
I'll see you.
- Bye.
- Yeah.
- The rest of you guys come with me.
- You got it.
A terrible thing.
What happened?
Jerk said he knew all
about farm equipment.
Expert mechanic, he said he was.
So they put him on a
tractor, and what does he do?
Falls in these disk blades.
Oh, that's horrible.
Oh, they all lie.
They come up here
saying they got all kinds of
experience, looking for work,
and look what happens.
And no more than an
hour after he gets here.
An awful way to die.
Sorry you had to come way out
here just to verify the obvious, Doc,
but rules is rules.
Yeah.
Okay, Jay. He's all yours.
Come on, you crackers.
Let's get back to work.
Come on, boys. Let's go.
So how did it happen, Buck?
The kid told me
he was a mechanic.
So I bring him out here,
tell him to figure out why
this tractor keeps stalling out.
He fires her up, and the next thing I
know, he's caught in the disk blades.
Well, couldn't you help him?
I was climbing
back into my pickup.
By the time I realized what
was happening, it was too late.
- Who the hell are you?
- I'm Ben Matlock.
I just gave that
boy a ride out here.
He seemed so excited
about working here,
and he seemed to know so
much about farm equipment.
- I just can't believe this happened.
- Well, you got no cause blaming me.
- I'm not blaming you. It's just...
- Okay, okay. Calm down, Buck.
We're all a little shook up.
Now, did anybody
else see the accident?
Yeah, one of the
farmhands... Lester.
- He was up in the cab.
- In the cab?
Couldn't he have turned
the damn thing off?
It happened too fast.
Look, mister, this
is a private farm,
and since I'm its foreman and
you ain't got no business being here,
- why don't you just get?
- Buck, take it easy.
You think I like seeing a
man get chewed up like that?
I'm just trying to find
out what happened.
- We all are, Mr...
- Matlock. Ben Matlock.
But you're kind of interfering
with my investigation here,
and I'm afraid I'm going to
have to ask you to move on.
I... I brought these
to give to Ramon.
He left them in my car.
Family pictures.
I'll send them back to El
Salvador with the rest of his effects.
- His address was in his wallet.
- Why don't you keep them with him?
I'm sure he would
have wanted it that way.
Yeah, okay.
Thank you.
E.J.
Excuse me. I couldn't
help but overhear.
Are you Ben Matlock the lawyer?
Retired lawyer.
What an honor. Al Matthews.
So you're... you're
a doctor, huh?
Well, not "a
doctor," the doctor.
If I ever retired, I don't know
what folks around here would do.
I do everything from pulling
teeth to delivering puppies.
But what on earth brings you to Oak
Creek? Not that I'm complaining, mind you.
I'm on my way to
Abbottsville to do some fishing.
Oh, I envy you.
I hear they're biting so well this
year you don't even need bait.
- Yeah?
- Fact is, I know a great motel up there.
The Sundown Lodge.
Owner's a friend of mine.
I'd be glad to give him a call
and tell him you're coming.
Well, thanks. I don't feel like
doing anymore driving today.
Is there a good motel
here in Oak Creek?
Let me put it this way,
there's only one motel in
Oak Creek, and it ain't the Ritz.
You change your
mind, just let me know.
- I'm in the book.
- Thanks.
Mrs. McArdle?
- Mrs. McArdle?
- Oh.
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
Well, you should be.
Someone did that to my cousin Esther
once, and she's been stuttering ever since.
I just wondered if you'd
heard anything from Ben.
Oh, not a peep.
Do you have any
idea where he went?
No, I don't.
But I do know one thing, a
man his age out on his own...
Well, it's just not healthy.
I remember when my
Uncle Clive went out on his...
Did I tell you about
my Uncle Clive?
- Well, I'm not sure.
- Well,
Uncle Clive didn't have it quite
altogether when he was home,
much less when
he was on his own.
Now, one time, he went
to New Orleans by himself,
and he ate one
peck of raw oysters
and two dozen chocolate-covered
donuts in one sitting,
fell in love with a
hoochy-coochy dancer and died.
Oh.
Strain was too much
for him. Don't you see?
- I see that.
- Well, wherever Mr. Matlock is,
I hope there's no
hoochy-coochy dancers.
I hope so, too.
Oh, they can be an awful
strain on a man his age.
Yes. Listen, if he calls, you'll let
me know right away, won't you?
Oh, yes. The poor,
defenseless thing.
Sure hope he doesn't
go like Uncle Clive.
- Yes.
- I lit a candle for him.
Light one for me.
I'd... I'd like a room.
Well, you need
to fill out this form,
and I need to see
a major credit card.
Yes, ma'am.
How long you staying?
- One night.
- Ah.
Uh, two, if there's
a good place to eat.
You'll just be staying the one.
The charge is $40 a night.
Ah.
You won't need more than
one bar of soap, will you?
No, I guess not.
Follow me. It's right over here.
- Do you own this place?
- Me and the bank, yep.
What about your husband?
I noticed you wear a ring.
My husband had a
stroke two years ago.
He's in a home
over in Montgomery.
Oh.
There you go.
Appreciate it if you
took short showers,
and keep the lights off
when you're not using them.
Uh-huh. Where's the bed?
You see that strap?
- Yeah.
- Give her a pull.
If you need anything
else, just dial zero.
I'll pick up eventually.
♪♪
Do you know who that is?
No. Haven't seen him before.
Good evening.
Ben Matlock. I saw you
out at the farm today.
Yeah. I'm out at
the farm every day.
Zacharia Tannenbaum.
Just call me Zack.
Well, Zack, you work out there?
Well, I have been
for the last 10 years,
ever since they foreclosed on
my property outside of Baker...
300 acres of bottom land.
Now it's just one
big subdivision.
Oh. What's good, Zack?
Well, the chicken-fried
steak ain't bad.
And the meatloaf neither,
as long as it's not more
than three days old.
I'll have chicken-fried steak.
That was a terrible thing
that happened out there.
Farming is a
dangerous profession.
Ain't no place for amateurs.
Did you see the accident?
I was putting hay
up in the barn.
First I heard of it
was when Mr. Rayhall
came roaring in to call the Doc.
Mr. Rayhall?
- Foreman. Buck Rayhall.
- Oh.
- Evening, Mr. Matlock.
- Good evening.
- Hello, Zack.
- Jones.
Don't tell me you
decided to spend the night.
Well, like I say, I'm not
exactly on a tight schedule.
How's the meatloaf, Ed?
- Made it yesterday.
- That's what I'll have then.
Well, early to
bed, early to rise.
And that pie ain't too bad either if you
don't mind chewing on the crust a while.
- Ah.
- Take it easy.
You, too.
Doc Matthews tells me you're on your
way to Abbottsville to do some fishing.
Yeah.
Is there going to be a
funeral? You know, for Ramon?
I'm having his body shipped back to
El Salvador so he can be buried there.
- That's very nice of you.
- Well, it's the least I could do.
Such a tragedy.
Farming's a
dangerous profession.
That's just what Zack said.
One chicken-fried
steak and one meatloaf.
Put that thing out.
Something wrong
with your dinner?
Oh, I guess I'm just not
used to that much gravy.
Order something else then,
and tell him to hold the gravy.
No, I'm... That's
okay. I'm full.
You'll hurt the guy's feelings
you don't have a piece of pie.
Oh, I can't. No.
Well, it's a nice time of
the year for a vacation.
I'm retired, Mr. Jones, and
so far it's been no vacation.
Nice to see you.
31, 32, 33.
Hi.
We're closed.
I was wondering if you
towed that truck in yet.
You know, the one that
belonged to Ramon Comaneros.
You know, the boy that was
killed in the accident today.
I thought he come
into town with you.
Well, he hitched a ride with me
because his truck broke down.
I thought maybe
you could, you know,
maybe sell it and send the
money to his family in El Salvador.
I don't know nothing about it.
Hmm. Well,
maybe the other fellow
that works here towed it in.
Ernie don't drive
the tow truck. I do.
He says it's 'cause the air
conditioning don't work no more.
He didn't mention it to you?
Nope.
Maybe he was busy.
Just between you and me, mister,
Ernie don't know the
meaning of the word "busy."
Huh.
Well, thanks anyway.
One, two, three...
Oh, Mr. Matlock,
I'm afraid I misplaced that
registration card you filled out today.
Could I trouble you to come
in now and fill out a new one?
Sure.
The insurance company's
real strict about such things.
No notes? No papers?
Nothing. Just some
fishing gear and clothes,
and me sneaking
around in there like a fool.
I told you.
Ben Matlock's a lawyer, not
some kind of federal agent.
Then why was he asking so many
damn questions out there today?
Well, I'm not crazy about
him being here either,
but I'm inclined to believe it's
just an unfortunate coincidence.
So I suggest we all relax.
Come morning, he'll get up,
eat some of Ed's
Teflon pancakes,
pack his things and be
out of our hair for good.
I'm telling you, somebody
was in my room last night.
Just because you found a
smudge on your undershirt?
This undershirt was
perfectly clean yesterday.
When Mrs. McArdle washes
my undershirts, they're clean.
Who are you accusing? Me?
All I'm saying is there's something about
this town and that boy's death yesterday
that just plain
don't feel right.
And now that somebody's
drug my undershirt into it,
I'm going to find out why.
I went in my room last night,
and I smelled something
funny like cigar smoke.
When I saw that smudge on my undershirt,
I knew somebody had been in my room.
You don't smoke, do you?
No, I don't, Sheriff.
And your hands
ain't particularly dirty.
I didn't say it was her.
It was somebody.
And they didn't take anything?
They just went through your stuff?
Yes, while I was over
at Ed's trying to eat.
Now, Mr. Matlock,
you have to admit
you don't exactly have
an open-and-shut case.
Somebody was in my room.
I can't exactly go arresting
anybody now, can I?
Somebody was in my room.
The Doc tells me
you just retired.
Yeah, but somebody
was in my room.
Why don't you just relax
and enjoy retirement?
That boy that was killed... His
truck broke down on the highway.
That's how come I
gave him a lift into town.
He made arrangements with
that fat fellow at the gas station.
- Ernie?
- Yeah.
He made arrangements with him to
tow his truck into town, and he never did.
Hmm.
Don't you think
that's a little strange?
Ernie probably forgot.
He does that with
irritating frequency.
Mr. Matlock, I was due over
at the Lowell half an hour ago.
Why don't you get
some breakfast?
Maybe things will look different
after some of Ed's gravy and eggs.
Hello?
Anybody here?
♪♪
May I help you?
I was wondering if you could tell
me something about the young man
that was killed in that accident
yesterday, Ramon Comaneros.
I happen to be working
on him even as we speak.
Working on him?
You know, preparing
him for shipment.
Believe me, it's going to
take me all day and then some.
What can I do you for?
Did you notice anything
unusual about the body?
You mean other than the fact
that it was mangled so bad I
had to get an anatomy book
to make sure I've got everything
facing in the right direction?
Okay, a dumb question.
When is he going
back to El Salvador?
Well, I'm sure E.J. has it
written down here somewhere.
I'm sorry, Paulie. Something's
come up. I'll have to call you back.
Matlock's at the funeral parlor.
E.J.'s gone, and that idiot
who works for him is there.
He must might say something.
For God's sakes,
why didn't you call me?
You've been on the phone.
Ramon will be
shipping out on the 24th.
This Thursday.
Excuse me for a sec.
Metcalf Undertaking.
Yeah?
Yeah.
I'm sorry. I forgot. It's against
policy to release any information
concerning one of our customers,
unless you're a blood relative.
That's okay. I understand.
Thanks for your time.
You did what?
I went to the undertaker's,
and I discovered something I
think you ought to know about.
Ramon didn't die till yesterday, but
arrangements to ship his body back...
I'm afraid I just don't have time
for this right now, Mr. Matlock.
But this is important, Sheriff.
I think Ramon was murdered.
I can't get away right now.
If you want to talk, you're
going to have to come out here.
Where are you?
Head down the highway towards
Lowell and turn left on Reservoir Road.
I'm at the Simpson Farm about
five miles down on the right.
Give me 10 minutes.
Much obliged.
You're welcome.
Mr. Matlock, are you all right?
I don't know.
I heard the report on my
radio. What the hell happened?
Somebody tried to kill me.
What?
A pickup truck
ran me off the road.
Deliberately?
Yes, deliberately. Ow!
He kept ramming
me until I lost control.
Take it easy, will you?
What did this pickup look like?
Cream-colored, an older model.
The paint was faded.
It looked like the
hood was all rusted.
I couldn't see
the license plate.
What is that? Battery acid?
Did you get a
look at the driver?
No. But whoever it was
didn't want me to tell you
what I found out
at the undertaker's.
Which was what, exactly?
I found out that arrangements
had already been made
to ship Ramon Comaneros' body to
El Salvador before he was even dead.
A freight order was
placed on the 17th,
three days before the accident.
- You're sure about that?
- I saw the books.
Tell me how this undertaker
knew he had a body to ship
before Ramon was even dead.
That boy's death was
no accident, Sheriff.
He was murdered.
I'll tell you what, Mr. Matlock.
Since I'm the one with
the star on my chest
and you're the one who's
getting patched up like an old tire,
let me handle this, all right?
Ow!
Sorry.
I ain't going to
do no such thing.
Come on, E.J.
You want to look at my books?
You go get yourself a search warrant.
Old Rusty over there let
Mr. Matlock look at your books.
Rusty's brain is so addled from
that rap garbage he listens to all day,
he don't hardly know up
from down, and you know it.
- He's hiding something, Sheriff.
- Mr. Matlock...
I am not, you nosy
old bag of gas.
Better that than
a bald-faced liar.
All right. That's enough.
E.J., if I have to, I
will get a warrant.
So either I see the books
now, or I see them later.
It's as simple as that.
You owe me, Dewey.
There. See?
Ramon Comaneros. Remains
to be shipped the 24th.
Order called in on...
Order called in on the 20th.
I made the call as soon as I
got back from picking him up.
It used to say 17th.
He's changed it.
How could I
change it? It's in ink.
He's changed the
whole page. Look.
See, the shade of ink is
different here from here.
All right, all right.
That's it. Get out.
Take it easy, E.J.
I've been more than
accommodating here, Dewey.
Now get him out of here before I'm
forced to shoot him for trespassing.
Come on, Mr. Matlock.
There's no sense giving E.J. any
more business than he's already got.
Ow! Stop pulling.
He changed the books,
Sheriff. You've got to believe me.
Ramon was murdered.
And chances are he
knows by whom and what for
and probably who
just tried to kill me.
Until we have proof, Mr. Matlock,
we are dead in the water.
I know that, and you know that.
Now, why don't you
go on back to the motel,
take some aspirin
and a nice hot bath,
and I'll see if I can track
down that pickup you described.
Ow!
You can't hit me like that.
You keep hitting me,
and I'll keep hitting you.
What's the matter?
Surprised to see me?
You look terrible.
What happened?
Somebody forced my car
off the road, turned it over.
But you know about
that, don't you?
Oh, you're talking
crazy again, Mr. Matlock.
Now what do you want?
More soap.
I'm going to stay a while
longer. Is that a problem?
Not for me, it isn't.
Meaning what?
Meaning there's some places
some people just plain don't belong,
and if they had any sense,
they'd clear out while they still can.
What's going on
in this town, Alice?
Here.
Because you know what?
Whatever it is, I've got a
feeling your heart's not in it.
That enough soap?
Yeah.
That will be fine.
Why would you go
putting something like that
down in your records
in the first place?
Why shouldn't I? It was a
legitimate business transaction.
Come on, E.J. Use your brain.
Hey, Comaneros was supposed
to arrive on the 17th, remember?
In order to guarantee shipment by
the 26th, I had to put the order in then.
Yeah. It ain't
his fault, Elliot.
It's this bozo's fault for not
taking care of that jackass lawyer
- when he had the chance.
- I couldn't!
A car came along before I could
make sure he was good and dead.
Yeah, well, next
time, I'll handle it.
There won't be a next time.
The state police were there.
They filed a report.
If he has another accident,
a lot of people are going to
start asking a lot of questions.
So what are we going to do?
Nothing.
We keep Mr. Matlock right here
to make sure he stays out of
trouble until the shipment goes out.
After that, it won't matter how
many questions people ask
because all their answers will
be on their way out of the country.
Michelle? Hi.
Hi.
I just got your message.
What's up?
Well, I thought we'd take the
current files back to the office,
and Ben can figure out what he
wants to do with the rest of them.
All right. Good idea.
Want to give me a hand?
Yeah.
So what kind of changes
have you got in the works?
For what?
Business. The office.
We are moving into new
offices now that Ben's retired.
I hadn't really
thought about it.
I have.
Michelle, the office
we've been using isn't you.
It's older,
established, like Ben.
People walk in there, they see
dark, heavy furniture, thick carpet.
They expect to see a gray-haired
fatherly man in a gray suit.
It's not you.
That's true, but...
We need something upscale.
Yeah. Windows.
A reception area with soft leather
couches and a beautiful secretary.
- Conrad.
- Okay, forget the couches.
A new office might
not be a bad idea.
Yeah. And computers...
State-of-the-art computers.
We've got to move
into the 20th century.
You know, Ben's
way wasn't so bad.
Yeah. That was Ben. Ben's
not going to be around anymore.
Yeah.
Good evening, Zack.
Lord have mercy.
What did the other
fellow look like?
I wish I knew.
How's the meatloaf tonight?
I wouldn't know. This
here is a chicken pot pie.
That looks just like meatloaf.
No, it don't.
I'll try the chicken pot pie.
Coming up.
Well, how were things
out at the farm today?
Any more accidents?
None of those, thank God.
About one of them a
year is all I can handle.
Was it a fatal accident
out there last year?
Yeah.
And the year before
that, as I recall.
Same thing happened?
Tractor tipped over
on somebody last year,
and before that, it seems to me
like a fellow got himself
caught in a hay baler.
Boy, that's awful.
Well, it's like I've been telling you,
farming is a dangerous business.
I've been at it
nigh on 62 years,
and I tell you it's remarkable that
I've still got my fingers and toes.
Zack.
Good evening, Mr. Rayhall.
Come on over here, Zack.
I want to talk to you about how
many hands we'll be needing next year.
Bring your plate. This
might take a while.
Sure, sure.
You're gonna have to excuse me.
He's the boss, you know.
Go ahead.
We're sorry. Your call
cannot be completed as dialed.
Please check the
number and try again.
Operator. May I help you?
Yeah. I've been trying to get through
to Atlanta for the past 10 minutes.
All the long distance
lines in the Oak Creek area
are down at the moment, sir.
Well, when will they be back up?
Well, I have no
way of knowing, sir.
Okay, thanks.
Thank you, sir.
I really hate this.
Well, here's your car, Mister.
The transmission is shot,
your universal joint is broken,
the frame is bent, and I can't
even find your water pump.
I don't suppose it runs.
Nope. I don't suppose it does.
Is there anywhere around
here I can rent a car?
The closest rental
place is up in Abbottsville.
But all the long distance
lines are down. I can't call out.
Maybe I can rent your car.
Don't got one.
I could always rent
you my Harley, though.
I guess you won't be going
anywhere anytime soon, will you?
So that's the idea now, is it?
Keep me bottled up here
so I can't go anywhere
and blow the whistle
about what's going on.
I don't know what
you're talking about.
How about renting me your car?
Sorry. I'm going to need it.
Look, Mr. Matlock, you know, we've
got some real good fishing around here.
Maybe you should just
relax and enjoy yourself.
As long as you can't
go nowhere, I mean.
We'll see about that.
Hey, Lucas, how are you doing?
Just fine, Dewey.
Mr. Matlock, we were
wondering what happened to you.
I bet you were.
He seems to think that things
aren't quite right around here.
Come here.
Pardon us for a minute.
Lucas, the guy just retired.
Now, he has nothing
to do but sit around
and try to invent some excitement
where there just ain't any.
Retired or no, he still pulls a
lot of weight in this state, Dewey.
You know why I'm here?
He called the governor. Collect.
But there's not a word of
truth to what he's saying.
I'm sorry. The heat is on.
Now, not only am I going
to investigate this thing,
I'm going to dot every I and
cross every T in the process.
So where do you want to start?
With the accident report on
that boy that died out at the farm.
You've got it.
You're not going
to see for yourself?
The sheriff here tells me there's
nothing to see, Mr. Matlock.
The accident happened
three days ago.
It appears to me that there's
absolutely nothing suspicious about it.
That's because
he wrote the report.
Whatever's going on
around here, he's in on it.
Mr. Matlock.
That undertaker could not
have known to change his books
after that failed attempt on
my life unless you called him.
Well, I've done
everything I can here.
Now, if you need a ride someplace,
I'd be glad to give you one.
No.
Okay.
Well, Dewey...
Next trip, I'll give you a couple
of jars of black-eyed peas.
- I had a bunch this year.
- Sounds good.
You're back.
Yeah. Yeah.
Something just kind
of drew me back.
I made some phone calls
while I was gone, though.
Boy, that's some place you've got your
husband in over there in Montgomery.
I don't know why
you called it a home.
That's one of the finest rehabilitation
centers for stroke victims in the country.
Expensive, though.
It's hard to believe how you pay your
bills on time every month, but you do.
You've got no business
prying into my personal affairs.
Somebody tried
to kill me, Alice.
It wasn't me.
- But you know who it was, don't you?
- No, I...
Just like you know how the undertaker
can afford that big house on the beach
and how Doc Matthews can afford to
keep that big yacht down at Pensacola.
Where did all that
money come from, Alice?
I can't tell you.
You have to, because like
I said, your heart's not in it.
You're not greedy like the others.
Your money goes for a good cause.
So that makes
you an outsider, too.
Sooner or later, the others
are going to realize that,
and they're going to come after
you just like they came after me.
You just leave me alone.
Mr. Rayhall?
This here's Conrad McMasters.
Hi.
He's looking for work.
Since we are a man
short, well, I thought...
- Did you talk to him?
- Yes, sir.
You're the man who does my
hiring and firing. What do you think?
Well, if he can do everything he says
he can do, I think we ought to hire him.
Then I'll give him a shot.
The starting pay is $6.25 an hour.
Zack will fill you in on all the rest.
Thanks.
Welcome aboard.
Where are you going?
Fishing.
I hear it's pretty good
up around the bend here.
It's a whole lot better
up near Abbottsville.
Get in. I'll give you a ride back
to the motel so's you can pack,
and I'll take you on up there.
First you want me to leave,
then you want me to stay.
Now you want me to leave again.
I wish you fellas would
make up your minds.
Did anybody ever tell you you
were paranoid, Mr. Matlock?
Sheriff, I've been meaning
to ask you something.
Those three racehorses
you've got up there in Kentucky...
Where did you get
that kind of money?
Hot roast beef...
hot turkey...
and one chicken and dumplings.
What do you mean he's fishing?
The sheriff saw him in Coral
Creek an hour ago, fishing.
Why would he go fishing?
Why not? It's what you said
we should tell him to do, ain't it?
What did he have to come
around here just now anyway?
I've got Ernie
keeping an eye on him.
For the meantime, I've
got a call from Atlanta.
They want to add to the
shipment going out tomorrow.
They're making another delivery?
Tomorrow afternoon.
With Matlock buzzing around
here like some infernal horsefly?
Why didn't you just
tell him to forget it?
Maybe I'll call him back
and let you tell him to forget it.
Would you like that?
Well, what are we going to do?
We're going to
get word to Rayhall,
and we're going to continue
to keep an eye on Mr. Matlock.
Yeah? Well, what if he goes
someplace we don't want him to go?
We'll make sure he doesn't.
I sure am glad I
brought some bug spray.
There's a lot of mosquitoes.
A lot of mosquitoes.
Yep.
Boy, I'd sure hate to be somebody
out here today without bug spray.
Be slapping mosquitoes
and green flies all day.
Yep. Ah.
This field here I
seeded two weeks ago.
Candleberries.
The field up ahead here, the
one we're going to just now,
that's also going
to be germinated.
Which field did that
guy get killed in?
Right here.
In fact, that's the disk
that killed him, right there.
We would move it, but we
can't get the damn tractor started,
so it just sits there reminding
everybody that comes by
how fragile and
transitory life is.
Did you see it happen?
No, sir.
But I was there when Lester pulled
that poor fellow out from them blades.
That was bad enough.
Ever see anything
like that happen before?
This is the third fatal
accident we've had up here.
Three fatal accidents?
Yes, sir.
It's a big operation.
Farming is a dangerous
profession. Just remember that.
What the hell is he doing here?
You're trespassing, Goldie.
You had no right to
get me fired like that.
I ain't working with a drunk, and I
don't want my boys working with a drunk,
so just get on out of here
before I have to call the sheriff.
My drinking ain't the
problem, old man, you are.
You get back on that contraption
and get out of here before
I run over the both of you.
Zack, look out!
Now, you get out of
here and you stay out,
unless you want another
whupping and some time in jail.
Whoa. Are you
all right? Sit down.
All of a sudden, it just occurred to
me how close I come to getting killed.
Well, it looked to me like you
were holding your own pretty good.
He'd have cut me wide open if
you hadn't have jumped in there.
Thanks. I owe you.
I owe you big.
Oh, come on. Let's
go get you patched up.
Will you be having a cookie?
Oatmeal and raisin.
Oh, I'm too upset to eat.
I hate this. It's just not fair.
First Ben goes off, then Conrad, and
neither one will tell us where they are.
You know what I feel like?
I feel the stupid little
women sitting at home
while the big strong men
are out hunting bears.
It's fish, dearie, not bears.
Now calm yourself.
Have a cookie.
You're right. If Ben's in
trouble, we should be there.
Oh, no, no. You don't
want to be taking off
like those two young women in
that movie, out on the road alone.
And look at the
trouble they got into.
We're not Thelma and
Louise, Mrs. McArdle.
We're just worried
about Ben and Conrad.
Now, girls, we women have always sat
and waited for the men to come home.
Haven't you ever seen
the play Riders to the Sea?
All the men at sea fishing, and
all the women at home waiting,
and the storm coming up, and the
boats capsizing, and the men all drowning,
and the women were all wailing
and keening and tearing their hair...
This wasn't a comedy, was it?
No, dearie, and neither is life.
But it's what it's meant to be.
The men go out to slay the dragons,
and the women wait and pray.
And there's always the
hoochy-coochy dancers.
- I have a client in half an hour.
- And I've got to get to court.
Thank you. You've been a
wonderful help, Mrs. McArdle.
- Bye, Mrs. McArdle.
- I try. I try.
Jake, get it saddled up.
Yes, ma'am. I'll have it
ready to ride in 20 minutes.
Get that hay in the barn
before the rain comes.
How's that arm?
Well, it's awful sore,
but I ain't complaining.
I'm just glad I've
still got an arm.
Looks like old Lester's in
thick with the boss, huh?
Yep.
Always has been.
Was he around when those other
men died in the accidents, too?
Well, yeah, now that you
mention it, seems to me he was.
You're going to have
to help me with this.
I'm sorry, Zack.
If you can't think of something to
do, I can think of something to do.
Who's that?
Oh, probably one of
Mr. Rayhall's friends from Atlanta.
They're always coming and going.
All right, boys.
We're finished here.
I'll be in the barn
if you need me.
You fellows go on
ahead. I'll catch up.
I'm going to go use the head.
I wish you'd do something
about all that damn dust out there.
I'm going to have to go
straight to the carwash after this.
Give us some more notice next
time, I'll get the road oiled down.
How much you got?
Two million.
Think you can fit it all in?
No problem.
Hey, you! What are you doing?
Mr. Rayhall!
He was listening at the window.
Look in the garage. I'll go
down and check the barn.
I need help.
Zack, that new guy
Conrad... Did he come in here?
No. He's supposed to be down
in our disk in the north field.
- Well, he ain't.
- Wait a minute.
Come on. Let's go.
What's the quickest
way out of town?
My pickup truck, I reckon.
- What the hell is going on?
- I'll tell you on the way. Come on.
Caught enough
for you, too, Ernie,
if you can stop slapping the
mosquitoes long enough to eat.
About time.
Get over there.
What's going on?
Just turn around.
What is this all about?
Conrad!
Oh, man. Hang on.
Everything's going to
be all right. Hang on.
Oh, I don't know
about that, Mr. Matlock.
It appears to me you
shot him pretty good.
What the hell are
you talking about?
The way I'm going to tell
it, you come into your room,
caught him in here, mistook
him for a burglar, and shot him,
knowing full well
he wasn't armed.
You'll never get away with
that. I don't even own a gun.
You do now.
The prints on it are
probably a little smudged.
I'm sure the
ballistics will match.
I'm afraid you're under arrest
for manslaughter, Mr. Matlock.
Okay. Get up.
He's still alive. You've
got to call a doctor.
Who? Doc Matthews?
He's busy. At least I'm pretty
sure that's what he would say.
Then I'll work on him myself.
No, you don't.
You're going to jail.
Now stand up before I have
to shoot you for resisting arrest.
You go to hell.
Then let me put it this way. Right
now your friend is alive, Mr. Matlock.
It would be a shame
if in all the excitement
I accidentally killed
him, wouldn't it?
Let's go.
I've got to get my pills.
What pills?
For my heart. Heart pills.
It's beating something fierce.
If I die, your scheme
goes out the window.
Where are they? In there?
In the closet.
Left-hand coat pocket.
No pills in here.
Maybe they're in
my right-hand pocket.
Matlock! Let me out of here!
Mat... Oh!
He shot my friend. He's
in there bleeding to death.
I gave him the key, but I didn't think
he was going to shoot anybody, I swear.
Then help me. I've got
to get him to a hospital.
I can't! They'll kill me!
Whose side are you on, Alice?
You've got to make up
your mind once and for all.
Are you going to keep being a part of
this, or are you going to help me stop it?
- Take my car.
- All right.
Tell me what's going on.
A bunch of hoods in Atlanta are
using the town to launder drug money.
They deliver it here, and then
we smuggle it out of the country...
Sometimes in shipments of
agricultural goods and sometimes...
In coffins,
with bodies of
dead farm workers.
We get a cut of
everything we handle.
Sometimes the people who deliver the
money need a place to spend the night.
I was drowning in medical
bills when this all started up.
Mr. Jones knew about it,
so the next thing I know,
he comes to me, and
I'm on their payroll, too.
Conrad must have found
out about it some way.
They shot him to get
him and me out of the way.
Now you hold on,
Conrad, you hear?
Hold on.
The money came in
from Atlanta this afternoon.
Maybe he found out about that.
This is Thursday.
Ramon's body gets
shipped out of here today.
Is Zack Tannenbaum in on this?
No. Believe or not,
most of the people in this town
are honest law-abiding citizens.
It's just the pillars of the
community who are corrupt.
The bleeding stopped.
His pulse is better.
Drop me off at the farm.
- What?
- Drop me off at the farm,
then take Conrad
to the hospital.
Then call the state police.
Ask for Lieutenant Wells. Tell
him to get down here right away.
If that body leaves this
town, so does all the proof.
What are you going to do?
I'm going to try to round me
up a good old-fashioned posse.
Okay. Goodbye.
- When's the truck due?
- Any minute.
Was that the sheriff?
He figures Matlock and Alice
are on their way to the hospital.
He's trying to catch up to them.
What if he can't? What
if they go to the cops?
As long as this casket's
gone by the time they get here,
we've got nothing
to worry about.
Matlock will just come off sounding
like a babbling lunatic again,
which means hurry the hell up.
I don't know if I
can fit it all in here.
Stick some into the body.
Nobody's got the stomach to
be poking around those remains.
Mr. Metcalf, the freight
truck just got here.
So did we.
Well, look who's here.
You always meet at the undertaker's,
or is this a special occasion?
Get out, all of you.
You're trespassing.
I've been telling the folks how you've
been laundering money for the mob.
What?
They'd kind of like to
see inside this casket.
Are you out of your mind?
There's a body in this casket.
A body and what else?
Zack, everybody,
Mr. Matlock's recently retired
because mentally he's
no longer competent.
Now, I hate to say it, but he's
senile, and he's making fools of you.
If he's so senile, why don't you just let
the rest of us take a look in that casket?
Because you've got no right to.
Are you going to move out of the
way, or do you want us to move you out?
- Yeah.
- We will.
So I'm no longer
mentally competent, huh?
Our man just pulled Dewey
over out on the highway.
They're bringing him in.
I'm sorry, Lieutenant. I know
the sheriff was a friend of yours.
Not anymore.
Yeah. Excuse me.
I talked to the doctors
just before I left.
Conrad's out of surgery,
and he's going to be all right.
Oh, thank you, Alice.
I guess it's time for
me to turn myself in.
I'll put in a good word for you.
And thanks again for Conrad.
You knew, didn't you?
- No.
- You did, too.
I didn't know one
thing about this party.
You weren't suspicious
when Mrs. McArdle
kicked you out of the
house this afternoon?
No. She said she was
having the rugs cleaned.
She kicks me out of
the house all the time.
- It came as a total surprise?
- Oh, yeah.
And you're having a good time?
I'm having a fine time.
I'm enjoying retirement.
I had a good time up at
Oak Creek... Now and then.
Any hoochy-coochy dancers?
Huh?
Never mind.
The easy life's the good life.
Here comes somebody else.
Excuse me. Let me go see.
Come in.
Oh. Come in, Frank.
I lost, Ben.
I know. I heard.
I shouldn't have fired you, Ben.
I'd like you to
handle my appeal.
Frank, I'm retired, you know.
Come on, Ben.
Nah.
I might call you
by the wrong name.
Men my age get forgetful.
Name your price.
Come on in, Frank.
Have some punch.
The spiked stuff's green.
Michelle.
- Guess what.
- What?
Frank just asked me
to handle his appeal.
- That's great.
- Are you going to do it?
You're not retiring?
No, I'm not retiring.
I guess I was feeling
sorry for myself.
I retired and thought
things would be better.
But I know how to do
one thing... Practice law...
And it brings me
a great deal of joy.
And anything that gives
that much happiness, why,
to give it up, I'd
be a perfect fool.
You're not retiring.
- Not retiring.
- You son of a gun.
- I'm glad.
- Oh, I am, too.
- Yeah.
- Oh. Ooh.
Sorry.
I'll tell you one thing.
I'm glad to be back.
www.tvsubtitles.net